{
    "data": {
        "title": "AWS Flashcards",
        "cards": [
            {
                "question": "What is S3?",
                "hint": "Used for files, not suitable to install an operating system on",
                "answer": "Object based storage"
            },
            {
                "question": "What are regions?",
                "hint": "This is as simple as it sounds",
                "answer": "Geographical regions"
            },
            {
                "question": "What is a group?",
                "hint": "How else can you differentiate developers, HR, finance etc?",
                "answer": "A place to store your users"
            },
            {
                "question": "What are availability zones?",
                "hint": "always at least 2 per region",
                "answer": "Collection of data centers"
            },
            {
                "question": "Do you use a private or public key to connect to EC2?",
                "hint": "You got this!",
                "answer": "Private Key"
            },
            {
                "question": "How do you design for failure in EC2",
                "hint": "cover all the bases",
                "answer": "Have one EC2 instance in each availability zone"
            },
            {
                "question": "Do you need to specify what region roles are in?",
                "hint": "You know this!",
                "answer": "No, roles are universal"
            },
            {
                "question": "Why use roles over Access Key ID's and Secret Access Keys?",
                "hint": "Two part answer",
                "answer": "Roles are more secure and easier to manage"
            },
            {
                "question": "When can you apply roles to EC2 instances?",
                "hint": "Extra Credit: they apply immediately",
                "answer": "Anytime"
            },
            {
                "question": "What is EC2?",
                "hint": "It's not serverless, it is a server!",
                "answer": "Compute based storage"
            },
            {
                "question": "What are security groups?",
                "hint": "Think internet safety!",
                "answer": "security groups are virtual firewalls in the cloud"
            },
            {
                "question": "How do you use security groups?",
                "hint": "think SSH, HTTP, HTTPS and RDP!",
                "answer": "You need to open ports to use security groups"
            },
            {
                "question": "What are the 4 types of EBS volumes?",
                "hint": "think SSH, HTTP, HTTPS and RDP!",
                "answer": "General, Provisional IOPS SSD, Throughout Optimized HDD, Cold Hard Disk HDD"
            },
            {
                "question": "What is EBS?",
                "hint": "It stands for Elastic Block Storage!",
                "answer": "EBS is a virtual disk that you install on your OS and virtual firewalls"
            },
            {
                "question": "What are the 11 instance types?",
                "hint": "Acronym Fight Dr. Mc Px!",
                "answer": "FGPA, IOPS, Graphics, High Disk Throughout, T2, Density, RAM, Main Choice, Compute, Graphics (pics), Extreme Memory"
            },
            {
                "question": "What do you use Redshift for?",
                "hint": "Two part answer!",
                "answer": "Business Intelligence or Data Warehousing"
            },
            {
                "question": "What does RDS stand for?",
                "hint": "Think database, table, row, column!",
                "answer": "Relational Databases"
            },
            {
                "question": "What do you use Dynamo DB for?",
                "hint": "Two part answer!",
                "answer": "Non-Relational Databases or autoscaling on the fly"
            },
            {
                "question": "What are the two key features of RDS?",
                "hint": "One is for disaster recovery and the other performance",
                "answer": "Multi-AZ and Read Replicas"
            },
            {
                "question": "What do you use Aurora or MySQL for?",
                "hint": "A type of database",
                "answer": "Relational Databases"
            }
        ]
    }
}
